[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the channel
today is another sultan straw ice cream
this is their maple bacon streusel
so what exactly is a streusel
it's um
i'm gonna put a link to a previous video
up here it's
it's just another crisp crumble pie
crust
cobbler
blah blah blah blah blah they're all the
same thing
so call it what you like that is what it
is but this one is a little bit
different
it has
candid bacon in it
so it's a maple ice cream with candied
bacon
streusel
this is a very popular salt and straw
ice cream so if you want to see what all
the fuss is about stick around and we'll
show you how to make it
[Music]
for this one we're going to start with
the maple brown sugar candied bacon
coat the bacon in the maple syrup and
the dark brown sugar well making sure
that both sides are loaded and then put
them on a baking tray add a little bit
more sugar to the top if you want and
then put them in the oven at 180c for 20
to 25 minutes it's gonna make your
kitchen smell fantastic
definitely use some foil though unless
you love cleaning burnt sugar from a pan
when it's done take it out and cool it
down quickly in the freezer
[Music]
next it's time for this
which is just another bloody version of
a crisp crumble cobbler thing like i
mentioned before
now i started with a typical internet
recipe and this was the result an
absolute train wreck it went straight in
the bin so instead we're going to use a
tried and tested recipe we used before
and that is the one from jenny's
fluffernutter ice cream i'll put the
link in the description for you
when it's all combined and baked at 175
c for 12 to 15 minutes remove it from
the oven and let it cool down at that
point take your bacon out of the freezer
and chop it up nice and small and add it
to the streusel
wang it in the freezer until it's
completely chilled
[Music]
now finally it's the ice cream base salt
and straw's own base but adjusted for
the maple syrup something to add is that
salt and straw use guru gum and
carrageenan in their tubs but xantham
gum in their recipes
but you can interchange for whatever
stabilizer you like just make sure you
keep the total amounts the same
so to your pan add 30 grams corn syrup
and 315 milliliters of milk and stir
well to combine and then add your 60
grams of sugar
which has your one gram of stabilizer
already mixed in then add 100 grams of
maple syrup and finally 30 grams of skim
milk powder
bring that up to the temperature
required for your stabilizer mine needs
65 degrees c so that's what i'm aiming
for when you're there remove it from the
heat and add your 315 mils of whipping
cream this is 35 fat
give it a quick stir and store it
covered in your fridge overnight
so when your ice cream base is chilled
take it out and put it in your icing
machine and churn it
the typical 15 to 30 minutes depending
on your machine when it's done start
loading up your tub ice cream and then
streusel
make sure the tub's fully loaded and pop
it in your freezer
[Music]
oh
there you go look a great tub i don't
know if that's in focus
maple look at a little piggy down there
i don't know if my wife is trying to
tell me something that you know
it's
nine o'clock on sunday morning and once
again i'm having ice cream for breakfast
this seems to be a recurring theme
let's get some scooped up and straighten
the bowl so we can see how this is
turned out
[Music]
bye
there we go you can see the little
pieces of bacon in there the streusel
i don't know why i said like an idiot
it's just me i guess
maple ice cream it looks good
let's just
dig in and see how it tastes
[Music]
okay
this is the first time
really that i've made uh
a sweet and savory ice cream
now my wife raised her eyebrow massively
when i said i wanted to do this flavor
and you know it's one of those things
that it's not very popular in the uk or
yet it's kind of coming over as the us
has done this for a long time
uk likes to absorb ideas from the us so
we thought we'd give it a try we love
bacon sugar obviously ice cream
obviously it's the whole channel
what does it taste like the maple ice
cream is great it's a really nice subtle
maple flavor not too much
the bacon does come through when you've
got it in but it comes through at the
end so once you've had that ice cream
and it's disappeared what you're left
with is that salty slightly sweet bacon
taste
which is obviously quite nice the
crumble is a nice little texture change
that's also very nice
is it a great combo i think it's a
personal thing
i like it i don't love it
but that's that's just me if you like
maple bacon combos you're gonna love
this i've had maple bacon donuts from
voodoo donuts before and they were great
how this is different i don't know it's
just i guess the donut is probably a
real
massive sugar hit straight away whereas
ice cream is a little bit different the
sugar it takes a little bit longer to
get on your palate so and being cold it
will change the way the flavors act
it's definitely a successful ice cream
make
for me
i'm kind of on the fence but if the
maple bacon thing is your cup of tea
then
definitely go ahead and try this
but i hope you enjoyed this video
remember to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week for another ice cream
make
[Music]